Kusum Pawar

SENIOR ASSOCIATE

Experienced professional with a passion for data and a track record of elevating companies through Excel proficiency with 8+ years of experience in HR Payroll and Finance.

Seeking a creative and challenging role to excel in achieving organizational and personal goals. Excited to contribute to your team's success.

✓ Jainkusum234@gmail.com

+918689835991

Mumbai, Maharashtra, IN

SKILLS

- Teamwork
- Leadership
- Time Management

Adaptability

EXPERIENCE

Senior Associate – Level 1

Apex Funds Services LLP Aug 2022 – Present

- The most important responsibilities of the above-mentioned designation are making (Trade Settlements) payments to the right client, at the right time. Making Domestic and Foreign FX payments to clients using SWIFT & IBAN numbers and internal transfers (Inter Company Transfers) within the SLA and before the Deadlines ends via various modes of payments like Telegraphic Transfer (TT), Bank Automated Clearing System (BACS) and Cheque's by various Bank line systems
- The most important responsibilities of the above-mentioned designation are making (Trade Settlement) payments to the right clients at the right time.
- Client money protection for funds for which deal has not been placed.
- Made internal transfers (Inter Company Transfers) within the SLA and before the deadline ends via various modes of payments like Telegraphic Transfer (TT), Bank Automated Clearing System (BACS) and Cheques.
- Handled all accounts payable and receivables for cash management.
- Mailed and interacting with the Management companies and clients, solving their queries and issues via E-Mail and conferences related to their investments.
- Deep Analyzing and researching for outstanding funds and payments client status on investment's
- Made payment and receipt entries on settlement of trade as per mandate (T+1 to T+4).
- Handling various regions like Ireland, US, Abu Dhabi, Dublin, Luxemburg and Canada, Malta.
- Making payment as per the instruction given in Invoices.
- Making redemption and subscription payment.
- Reconciling and investigating if payment returns or if there is an issue with payment.
- Monitoring funds in bank accounts and doing internal transfers between accounts if needed.
- Tracking Inflow and Outflow of funds for various accounts.

Subject Matter Expert Level 11.2 Accenture Solutions Pvt Ltd May 2021 - Aug 2022

- Started career with learning new client which has gone live September 2021
- Focused on Knowledge Transfer Training given to us from US Client
- Learned Various processes in Three Months such as Banking Process, Time and Attendance, Promotions, Retro
 payment, tax validations, Severance etc.
- Learned New System to work on ADP, People Soft and Service Now
- Process Pass thru which run on daily basis from people soft to APD to pass on the transactions.
- Process Severance payments to terminated employees on monthly or weekly basis.
- Update ADP with employees who are new to organizations.
- Manage interaction with ADP at the time of Pay run so all the employees are paid correctly.
- Upload Garnishments in ADP so that ADP can collect it directly from there.
- Process Overpaid Cheques which are returned by employees to us.
- Learned activity processed during Payroll as pre-payroll, payroll, and post payroll.
- Make sure to process the request with 100% focus and 100 % accuracy and have learned the process with 100% focus.
- Made SOPs for the all the processes.

Analyst

Wipro Pvt Ltd May 2018 - May 2021

- The most important responsibilities of the above-mentioned designation are handling the employee data.
- Made promotions for employees both off cycle as well as on cycle.
- Maintained data in SAP for employee's monthly addition and deductions.
- Make one off payments to employees that is they are not paid on monthly basis (E.g., bonus, referral
 amount etc.)
- Processed loan to employee for travelling and recovering loan monthly from employee.
- Processed education claim to employee for their children
- Updated BACS and account no for employee in SAP
- Running PA40 and using PA30 and PA20 in SAP and using queries for data from SAP.
- I worked within SLAs and before deadlines for different processes at a time.
- Trained to new trainees.
- Handled high volumes and supported team while doing stretches whenever required.
- Learned whole Payroll process as pre-payroll, payroll, and post payroll.
- Learned Multiple Reports which effect on employee's paycheck and reduce the risk of employee getting overpaid.
- I also make sure to process the request with 100% focus and 100 % accuracy and have learned the process with 100% focus.

- I have also maintained the notes of process and do use them during difficulties.
- We maintain records of employee in Employee Central Pay and Employee Center which is also known as Partner connect.
- Handled On cycle process in SAP.
- Solving errors for partner which occur during on-cycle.
- Process reports during open for correction.

Associate

State Street Syntel Pvt. Ltd. Feb 2016 - May 2018

- The most important responsibilities of the above-mentioned designation are making (Trade Settlement) payments to the right clients at the right time.
- Made Domestic and Foreign FX payments using IBAN & Swift codes.
- Client money protection for funds for which deal has not been placed.
- Made internal transfers (Inter Company Transfers) within the SLA and before the deadline ends via various modes of payments like Telegraphic Transfer (TT), Bank Automated Clearing System (BACS) and Cheques.
- Handled all accounts payable and receivables for cash management.
- RBS, NatWest, Barclays and HSBC bank line user.
- Mailed and interacting with the Management companies and clients, solving their queries and issues via E-Mail and conferences related to their investments.
- Deep Analyzing and researching for outstanding funds and payments client status on investment's
- Processed multiple tasks of different management companies at a time.
- Maintained Treasury and sending treasury balance to management company, so that they come to know whether they are dealing with profit or not.
- Made payment and receipt entries on settlement of trade as per mandate (T+1 to T+4).
- Reconciliation of Clients books of accounts on daily basis.
- Trained to new trainees.

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

State Street Syntel

- Appreciated through Spot Appreciation Method for being Vigilant and avoiding double payment to client of a huge amount and for saving a breach.
- Received "Syntel champ" award from higher management for highest productivity and zero errors.
- Rewarded as Engaged Behavior Reward for Quarterly Performance
- Rewarded as one of the values (Adaptive) Award.
- Appreciation from clients

Wipro Pvt Ltd

- Appreciated by seniors and managers for speed and accuracy.
- Appreciated for being vigilant and avoiding payment to GEC employees.

- · Rewarded with Blaze Award for outstanding performance during covid pandemic.
- Promoted to Analyst
- Completed Go Live Process smoothly in 3 months with Accenture successfully with No Escalation
 - ❖ Apex:
- Received Champs of the weeks Twice in 1 year.
- Received Spot award for outstanding performance.
- Got Promoted to SA within the first cycle of promotions.

EDUCATION

Master's in business administration in Finance D.Y Patil University, Pune July 2023 FIRST CLASS

Bachelor Of Account and Finance Mumbai University Jun 2014 FIRST CLASS

Higher Secondary School Certificate Maharashtra State Board May 2011 FIRST CLASS

Secondary School Certificate Maharashtra State Board Mar 2009 SECOND CLASS

PERSONAL INFO

DATE OF BIRTH

13th January 1994

GENDER

Female

MARITAL STATUS

Married

HOBBIESs

Playing Carrom, Dancing

	C-704, Kailash Park, Lalashet, Gadhav Naka, I	3handup
١	West, Mumbai-400078	

LANGUAGES		
English	Marathi	Hindi